Bruce Jackson and Diane Christian collection
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress
Bruce Jackson and Diane Christian collection circa 1961-1988
AFC 2011/009
Jackson, Bruce, 1936-; Christian, Diane, 1939-
approximately 3346 items
5 containers
27.5 linear feet
5 containers; approximately 1400 items
197 sound cassettes: analog
1062 sound tape reels (5 in., 7 in., 10 in.): analog
10 photographs: film positives, color; 35 mm
3 photographs: prints, black and white; 5 x 6 in. and smaller
approximately 614 film elements
approximately 60 videocassettes
Archive of Folk Culture, American Folklife Center, Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
Documentation of fieldwork conducted by Bruce Jackson in prisons in Indiana, Missouri, and Texas; recordings at concerts and festivals including the Newport Folk Festival 1963-1965, 1967-1968; interviews conducted at various events including Resurrection City, 1968; interviews with and performances by various blues artists, folk artists, and others including poets and literary figures, 1961-1980s; production footage for film documentaries on various topics by Bruce Jackson and Diane Christian.
Provenance
Bruce Jackson and Diane Christian; purchase 2010-2011.
Other Repositories
These collections are in the Archives and Manuscripts Collections, University at Buffalo Libraries:
Bruce Jackson papers (16/4F/133)
Bruce Jackson Campus Revolt collection (16/4F/134)
Related Material
These collections are at the American Folklife Center, Library of Congress:
Bruce Jackson Texas prison songs, 1964 (AFC 1965/011)
Bruce Jackson Texas prison songs, 1965-1966 (AFC 1967/009)
Folklore and Seeing: Photographs from Cummins Prison, 1915-2010, Lecture by Bruce Jackson (AFC 2010/006)
Bruce Jackson oral history interview conducted Nancy Groce (AFC 2010/014)
Access and Restrictions
The Bruce Jackson and Diane Christian collection is open to research. To request materials, please contact the Folklife Reading Room at https://hdl.loc.gov/loc.afc/folklife.contact
Certain restrictions to use or copying of materials may apply.
Biographical Note
Bruce Jackson, born in Brooklyn, New York and raised in New Jersey, has lived most of his life in Buffalo, New York, but traveled around the U.S. to do field work. Together with Diane Christian he created five film documentaries, and has co-hosted the Buffalo Film Seminar series since its inception in 2000. He is SUNY Distinguished Professor and James Agee Professor of American Culture at University of Buffalo, and in addition to film documentaries he is also widely published, and has staged numerous photography exhibits.
Diane Christian was born in Brooklyn and raised in Rochester, New York. After nearly eight years as a nun with the Sisters of Saint Joseph (in Buffalo), she left for a career in higher education. Christian began teaching at the University at Buffalo in 1969, and met Bruce Jackson the following year. They married in 1973, and over the course of their 50 years together have built a working partnership that has yielded not only five film documentaries, but also co-hosting duties for the Buffalo Film Seminar series, as well as other professional collaborations. She has published both poetry and non-fiction, and continues to teach in the Department of English at University of Buffalo, where she is SUNY Distinguished Teaching Professor.
Scope and Content
Documentation of fieldwork conducted by Bruce Jackson in prisons in Indiana, Missouri, and Texas; recordings at concerts and festivals including the Newport Folk Festival 1963-1965, 1967-1968; interviews conducted at various events including Resurrection City, 1968; interviews with and performances by various blues artists, folk artists, and others including poets and literary figures, 1961-1980s; production footage for film documentaries on various topics by Bruce Jackson and Diane Christian.
Arrangement
The Bruce Jackson and Diane Christian collection is organized in four series:
1. Manuscript Materials
2. Sound Recordings
3. Graphic Materials
4. Moving Images
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the LC Catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically.
People
Christian, Diane, 1939-; Creeley, Robert, 1926-2005.; Hurt, Mississippi John, 1892-1966.; Jackson, Bruce, 1936-; James, Skip, 1902-1969.; Kunstler, William M. (William Moses), 1919-1995.; McClure, Michael.; Muddy Waters, 1915-1983.; Seeger, Pete, 1919-2004.
Organizations
Newport Folk Festival.
Subjects
African American prisoners.; Blues (Music)--1961-1970.; Death row inmates--United States.; Death row--United States.; Ex-nuns--United States--Interviews.; Folk festivals--United States.; Folk music--United States.; Poor People's Campaign.; Prisons--Indiana.; Prisons--Missouri.; Prisons--Texas.; Veterans--United States--Interviews.
Form/Genre
Correspondence.; Documentary films.; Field recordings.; Film.; Interviews.; Manuscripts.; Oral histories.; Photographs.; Sound recordings.; Videocassettes.
Container List
- Series 1: Manuscript Materials
  - Correspondence, 1965 (Box-folder 1/1)
  - Catalog of recordings, undated (Box-folder 1/2)
    Typed document
  - Tape logs (original), undated (Box-folder 1/3)
  - Logs for songs recorded at various prisons, undated (Box-folder 1/4)
    Also includes transcribed jokes. Typed and handwritten document.
  - Tapes from Vanguard, undated (Box-folder 1/5)
  - Tapes from Guy Carawan, undated (Box-folder 1/6)
  - Indiana State Prison and Missouri Penitentiary: catalogs (1 of 2), 1962-1964 (Box-folder 1/7)
  - Indiana State Prison and Missouri Penitentiary: catalogs (2 of 2), 1962-1964 (Box-folder 1/8)
  - Indiana State Prison: transcripts (1 of 3), circa 1962 (Box-folder 1/9)
  - Indiana State Prison: transcripts (2 of 3), circa 1962 (Box-folder 1/10)
  - Indiana State Prison: transcripts (3 of 3), circa 1962 (Box-folder 1/11)
  - Missouri State Prison: transcripts (1 of 2), circa 1962-1964 (Box-folder 1/12)
  - Missouri State Prison: transcripts (2 of 2), circa 1962-1964 (Box-folder 1/13)
  - Texas prison interviews: transcripts, binder 3, undated (Box-folder 2/1)
    There is no binder 1 or 2 with the collection
  - Texas prison interviews: transcripts, binder 4, undated (Box-folder 2/2)
  - Prison interviews: transcripts (1 of 2), undated (Box-folder 2/3)
  - Prison interviews: transcripts (2 of 2), undated (Box-folder 2/4)
  - Dempsey Blackwell: interview transcript, undated (Box-folder 2/5)
  - W.C. (Dutch) Erikson: interview transcript; gospel group: transcriptions (1 of 2), undated (Box-folder 2/6)
  - W.C. (Dutch) Erikson: interview transcript; gospel group: transcriptions (2 of 2), undated (Box-folder 2/7)
  - Sonny Lucchese: transcript for interview, March 17, 1966 (Box-folder 2/8)
  - Bill McDonald: transcripts of interviews, undated (Box-folder 3/1)
  - Ramsey 2: Clark McDonald interview transcript (1 of 2), undated (Box-folder 3/2)
  - Ramsey 2: Clark McDonald interview transcript (2 of 2), undated (Box-folder 3/3)
  - Interview transcripts: Jack Rice, Della McCutcheon, John Breen, James Miller, Bill Woodward, undated (Box-folder 3/4)
    Transcripts for individual interviews.
  - Transcripts for non-metered interviews, undated (Box-folder 3/5)
  - Audio tape boxes (photocopies) (1 of 2), undated (Box-folder 3/6)
    Photocopies arrived with the collection
  - Audio tape boxes (photocopies) (2 of 2), undated (Box-folder 3/7)
  - Audio tape containers for SR1146-1160 (photocopies), undated (Box-folder 3/8)
  - Materials from sound recording containers (1 of 3), undated (Box-folder 4/1)
  - Materials from sound recording containers (2 of 3), undated (Box-folder 4/2)
  - Materials from sound recording containers (3 of 3), undated (Box-folder 4/3)
  - Materials from moving image containers (MV001-050), undated (Box-folder 4/4)
  - Materials from moving image containers (MV051-100), undated (Box-folder 4/5)
  - Materials from moving image containers (MV101-150), undated (Box-folder 4/6)
  - Materials from moving image containers (MV151-200), undated (Box-folder 4/7)
  - Materials from moving image containers (MV201-282), undated (Box-folder 4/8)
  - Materials from moving image containers (MV296-302), undated (Box-folder 4/9)
  - Empty sound recording boxes, undated (Box 5)
    Empty containers from selected rehoused sound recordings: SR0479, SR0480, SR0481, SR0482, SR0757, SR0933, SR0938, and SR0939.
- Series 2: Sound Recordings
  Information about the sound recordings is derived from sound recording containers, accompanying documentation, and communications with Bruce Jackson. Titles are a compilation of basic details from tape containers, primarily tape box spines. Recognizable abbreviations are silently expanded. The processor added information that appears in brackets, usually the better-known title of a song or a performer, etc. Question marks indicate information that has not been transcribed (when in brackets) or when the transcription is conjecture. Not all of the information from the tape boxes has been transcribed. Digital images of the containers are available on request. The containers for SR0087 and SR0934 arrived at AFC empty, and each was assigned an ID number in error.
  - Subseries 1: Documentaries, fieldwork, and other projects
  - Sub-subseries 1: Creeley
    Sound recordings for the three Creeley film projects: "Willy's Reading" (1982), "Creeley" (1988), and "Creeley and the Persistence of Verse" (2001), as well as related recordings.
    - 1 / Creeley, circa 1982-1984, AFC 2011/009: SR1078; 1 sound cassette (60 min.): analog
      Tape 1.
    - 2 / [Creeley], circa 1982-1984, AFC 2011/009: SR1079; 1 sound cassette (60 min.): analog
      Tape 2. Side 1: reels 6 and 7. Side 2: reel 8. This tape may be Tape 3, and is a dub of the original.
    - 3 / Creeley, circa 1982-1984, AFC 2011/009: SR1080; 1 sound cassette (60 min.): analog
      Tape 3. Side 1: 8-13. Side 2: 14-15.
    - 4 / Creeley, circa 1982-1984, AFC 2011/009: SR1081; 1 sound cassette (60 min.): analog
      Tape 4.
    - 5 / MA-60 / Creeley and Doris, July 18, 1984, AFC 2011/009: SR1082; 1 sound cassette (60 min.): analog
      Tape 5. Bob and Doris. Side 1: restaurant / Doris's house. Side 2: Doris's house / Ed and Jennifer D[?].
    - 6 / Bob Creeley, Ed and Jennifer Dorn [?] / Bob's wed [wedding?] / Naropa class, July 18, 1984, AFC 2011/009: SR1083; 1 sound cassette (60 min.): analog
      Tape 6. Side 1: Doris's [?] / last mag [?]. Side 2 Naropa class. "Naropa" is Naropa University, in Boulder, Colorado.
    - 7 / Bob's Naropa class, July 18, 1984, AFC 2011/009: SR1084; 1 sound cassette (60 min.): analog
      Tape 7. See note for SR1083.
    - 8 / MOP / Bob's Naropa Class 7-18-84 / Allen Ginsberg, sync 7-19-84, July 18-19, 1984, AFC 2011/009: SR1085; 1 sound cassette (60 min.): analog
      Tape 8. Side 1: Bob's Naropa class MOP [mit out picture; i.e., without picture], July 18. Side 2: Allen Ginsberg sync, July 19. See note for SR1083.
    - 9 / Allen Ginsberg / MOP, July 18, 1984, AFC 2011/009: SR1086; 1 sound cassette (60 min.): analog
      Tape 9. Sides 1 and 2: Allen Ginsberg in Boulder [Colorado]; no picture. See note for SR1083.
    - 10 / End of Ginsberg MOP / Wild Outside Apt / Bob's Friday Lecture, circa July 18, 1984, AFC 2011/009: SR1087; 1 sound cassette (60 min.): analog
      Tape 10. Side 1: First few minutes Ginsberg MOP [mit out picture]; [?] outside apartment; Allen, Bob, Phil with [?], others with [?]. Side 2: Bob's Friday class.
    - 11 / Bob's Class, July 20, 1984, AFC 2011/009: SR1088; 1 sound cassette (60 min.): analog
      Tape 11. Both tape sides: Bob's class / Naropa.
    - 12 / Martín Espada / Int on Bob / Others come in / Boulder, circa 1982-1984, AFC 2011/009: SR1089; 1 sound cassette (90 min.): analog
      Tape 12. Interview on Bob; others join in.
    - 13 / Bob, Bruce, Diane, Henri Diege, September 25, 1984, AFC 2011/009: SR1090; 1 sound cassette (90 min.): analog
      Tape 13. Bob, Bruce, Henri Diege / 96 Rumsey / (10 min.). Side 2: Bob, Bruce, Henri, Diane.
    - 14 / Creeley / UB Class, October 23, 1984, AFC 2011/009: SR1091; 1 sound cassette (60 min.): analog
      Tape 14.
    - 15 / Creeley UB, October 23, 1984, AFC 2011/009: SR1092; 1 sound cassette (60 min.): analog
      Tape 15.
    - 16 / Creeley, October 23, 1984, AFC 2011/009: SR1093; 1 sound cassette (90 min.): analog
      Tape 16. Both tape sides: wild take [?]
    - 17 / Creeley Phila / Temple, November 8, 1984, AFC 2011/009: SR1094; 1 sound cassette (60 min.): analog
      Tape 17. Both tape sides: Temple [University?], Philadelphia
    - 18 / Creeley / Temple, November 8, 1984, AFC 2011/009: SR1095; 1 sound cassette (90 min.): analog
      Tape 18. Both tape sides: Creeley reading, Temple [University?], Philadelphia
    - 19 / Creeley / Dub of German Reading, June 11, 1983, AFC 2011/009: SR1096; 1 sound cassette (60 min.): analog
      Tape 19.
    - 21 / Creeley / MA / ME, possibly December 7, 1984, AFC 2011/009: SR1097; 1 sound cassette (60 min.): analog
      Tape 21.The month and day are noted in the documentation but not the year.
      - 1. Harvard Square
      - 2. Bob, [?] - Maine
      - 3. Clock
      - 4. [?]
    - 22 / Creeley, circa 1982-1984, AFC 2011/009: SR1098; 1 sound cassette (90 min.): analog
      Tape 22. Creeley / Cambridge
    - 23 / Creeley, circa 1982-1984, AFC 2011/009: SR1099; 1 sound cassette (90 min.): analog
      Tape 23.
    - 24 / Creeley, circa 1982-1984, AFC 2011/009: SR1100; 1 sound cassette (90 min.): analog
      Tape 24. Side A: end 2
    - 25 / Creeley, circa 1982-1984, AFC 2011/009: SR1101; 1 sound cassette (90 min.): analog
      Tape 25.
    - 26 / Creeley, circa 1982-1984, AFC 2011/009: SR1102; 1 sound cassette (90 min.): analog
      Tape 26. Side 1: Bob - looking at photos. Side 2: Bob - [?].
    - 27 / Creeley, November 16, 1984, AFC 2011/009: SR1103; 1 sound cassette (60 min.): analog
      Tape 27. Irene AEB 1 with Steve Lacy Ensemble / Futurities (on Poem of Robert Creeley)
    - 28 / Creeley, circa 1982-1984, AFC 2011/009: SR1104; 1 sound cassette (60 min.): analog
      Tape 28. Side 1: Lacy 2. Side 2: 6B dub.
    - 29 / Creeley / MLA Reading, December 29, 1984, AFC 2011/009: SR1105; 1 sound cassette (60 min.): analog
      Tape 29. Both tape sides: MLA Reading. Project [?] panel. MLA may be the Modern Language Association.
    - 30 / Creeley / Wild at MLA / Wild at Maine / Sync at AK / 1-13, December 29, 1984, AFC 2011/009: SR1106; 1 sound cassette (60 min.): analog
      Tape 30. "Wild" here probably means wild sound. "AK" is Albright-Knox Art Gallery, in Buffalo, New York.
      - Side 1
      - Wild at MLA: 1) Lobby 2) Bookshop 3) Bookshop
      - Wild at Maine: House - window / Trees in [?] with sync [?]
      - Side 2
      - Bob and P[?] at Albright House / 1-13 / sync
    - 31 / MLA Panel: Papers and Discussion, December 29, 1984, AFC 2011/009: SR1107; 1 sound cassette (60 min.): analog
      Tape 31.
    - 32 / Creeley / MLA Session on WMDG, December 29, 1984, AFC 2011/009: SR1108; 1 sound cassette (90 min.): analog
      Tape 32. Side 1: Room and Bob on WMDG. Side 2: Papers on WMDG.
    - 33 / Creeley / Albright Knox / Podium Tape WMDG / Dolby, January 14, 1985, AFC 2011/009: SR1109; 1 sound cassette (90 min.): analog
      Tape 33. See note for SR1106.
    - 34 / Creeley / AK Reading, January 14, 1985, AFC 2011/009: SR1110; 1 sound cassette (90 min.): analog
      Tape 34. See note for SR1106.
    - 34 / Creeley Albright Knox Sync Dub, January 14, 1985, AFC 2011/009: SR1137; 1 sound cassette (90 min.): analog
      Tape 34 (dub). Albright-Knox reading. See notes for SR1106 and SR1110.
    - 35 / Creeley and Ashbery NPR, January 26, 1985, AFC 2011/009: SR1111; 1 sound cassette (60 min.): analog
      Tape 35. "Ashbery" is John Ashbery, a poet.
    - 36 / Cemetery Poem, November 1985, AFC 2011/009: SR1112; 1 sound cassette (60 min.): analog
      Tape 36.
    - 1 / Bob Creeley: Albright-Knox Reading, March 8, 1981, AFC 2011/009: SR1153; 1 sound cassette (90 min.): analog
      Creeley reading at Albright-Knox. Begins with chatter - mic is attached to Bob. Then Murray Schwartz's off-mic intro / then reading. See note for SR1106.
    - 2 / Bob Creeley: Albright-Knox Reading, March 8, 1981, AFC 2011/009: SR1154; 1 sound cassette (90 min.): analog
      Creeley reading at Albright-Knox. See note for SR1106.
    - 3 / Bob Creeley and Diane / Buffalo, March 30, 1981, AFC 2011/009: SR1155; 1 sound cassette (90 min.): analog
      Bob Creeley: talking with Diane and reading poems. Soundtrack for 000 rolls 9-11. Creeley rolls 4, 5, 6 at his house.
    - Bob Creeley / Soundtrack for rolls 7 and 8, June 9, 1981, AFC 2011/009: SR1156; 1 sound cassette (60 min.): analog
      Side A: Bob and Irene / rolls 7 and 8. Bob Creeley, reading poems and talking with Diane and Bruce at his house.
    - Bob Creeley / Soundtrack for roll 9, June 9, 1981, AFC 2011/009: SR1157; 1 sound cassette (90 min.): analog
      Side 1: Bob and Diane / Roll 9. Bob Creeley at his house, talking with Bruce and Diane and Willie.
    - Creeley 1 dub, circa 1982-1984, AFC 2011/009: SR1113; 1 sound cassette (60 min.): analog
    - Creeley 2 dub, circa 1982-1984, AFC 2011/009: SR1114; 1 sound cassette (60 min.): analog
    - Creeley 3 dub, circa 1982-1984, AFC 2011/009: SR1115; 1 sound cassette (60 min.): analog
    - Creeley 4 dub, circa 1982-1984, AFC 2011/009: SR1116; 1 sound cassette (60 min.): analog
    - Creeley 5 dub, circa 1982-1984, AFC 2011/009: SR1117; 1 sound cassette (60 min.): analog
    - Creeley 6 dub, circa 1982-1984, AFC 2011/009: SR1118; 1 sound cassette (60 min.): analog
    - Creeley 7 dub, circa 1982-1984, AFC 2011/009: SR1119; 1 sound cassette (60 min.): analog
    - Creeley 8 dub, circa 1982-1984, AFC 2011/009: SR1120; 1 sound cassette (60 min.): analog
    - Creeley 9 dub, circa 1982-1984, AFC 2011/009: SR1121; 1 sound cassette (60 min.): analog
    - Creeley 10 dub, circa 1982-1984, AFC 2011/009: SR1122; 1 sound cassette (60 min.): analog
    - Creeley 11 dub, circa 1982-1984, AFC 2011/009: SR1123; 1 sound cassette (90 min.): analog
    - Creeley 13 dub, circa 1982-1984, AFC 2011/009: SR1124; 1 sound cassette (90 min.): analog
    - Creeley 14 dub, circa 1982-1984, AFC 2011/009: SR1125; 1 sound cassette (60 min.): analog
    - Creeley 15 dub, circa 1982-1984, AFC 2011/009: SR1127; 1 sound cassette (60 min.): analog
    - Creeley 17 dub, circa 1982-1984, AFC 2011/009: SR1128; 1 sound cassette (60 min.): analog
    - Creeley 18 dub, circa 1982-1984, AFC 2011/009: SR1129; 1 sound cassette (90 min.): analog
      Temple [Temple University?]
    - Creeley 19 dub, circa 1982-1984, AFC 2011/009: SR1126; 1 sound cassette (60 min.): analog
      UB class 1023
    - Creeley 22 dub, circa 1982-1984, AFC 2011/009: SR1130; 1 sound cassette (90 min.): analog
    - Creeley 23 dub, circa 1982-1984, AFC 2011/009: SR1131; 1 sound cassette (90 min.): analog
    - Creeley 24 dub, circa 1982-1984, AFC 2011/009: SR1132; 1 sound cassette (90 min.): analog
    - Creeley 25 dub, circa 1982-1984, AFC 2011/009: SR1133; 1 sound cassette (90 min.): analog
    - Creeley 26 dub [copy 1?], circa 1982-1984, AFC 2011/009: SR1134; 1 sound cassette (90 min.): analog
    - Creeley 26 dub [copy 2?], circa 1982-1984, AFC 2011/009: SR1135; 1 sound cassette (90 min.): analog
      [?] photos
    - Creeley 32 dub, circa 1982-1984, AFC 2011/009: SR1136; 1 sound cassette (90 min.): analog
      MLA room, int [interview?], bib [?]
  - Sub-subseries 2: Recordings made in prisons
    This includes recordings made in Arkansas, Indiana, Missouri, and Texas.
    - I-1 / 105 / 1312 / Indiana State Prison / #1: Hillbilly / Ferguson / Turpin / Bell / others, circa 1962, AFC 2011/009: SR0889; 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
      The spine label is from the Archives of Folk and Primitive Music, Indiana University.
    - I-2 / 106 / 1313 / Indiana State Prison / #2: Hillbilly / Ferguson / Turpin / Bell / others, circa 1962, AFC 2011/009: SR0890; 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
    - I-3 / 107 / 1314 / Indiana State Prison / #3: Sociological / Richard Woods on prostitution, dope, circa 1962, AFC 2011/009: SR0891; 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
    - I-5 / 108 / 1315 / Indiana State Prison / #4: Scatological: Kenny Grenert / Bell / Ferguson, circa 1962, AFC 2011/009: SR0892; 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
    - I-7 / 111 / 1316 / Indiana State Prison / #7: Blues / Eugene Rhodes, 1962, AFC 2011/009: SR0893; 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
      Labels on the box are from the Archives of Folk and Primitive Music, Indiana University.
      - 1. Talk on personal experiences, on blues and other forms of folk music, on Blind Lemon and other singers he knew
      - 2. O Lordy Mama (Moss)
      - 3. Evil Hearted Woman (Fuller)
        Fragment
    - I-8 / 112 / 1317 / Indiana State Prison / #8: Blues / Eugene Rhodes, March 31, 1962, AFC 2011/009: SR0894; 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
      - 1. Don't Want Me No More (Moss)
      - 2. Step It Up and Go (Fuller)
      - 3. [unidentified]
        Instrumental
      - 4. If You See My Saviour
      - 5. Trucking Little Baby (Fuller)
      - 6. Good Morning Little Schoolgirl
      - 7. Talk on Leadbelly
      - 8. Dough Rolling Papa (Moss)
      - 9. If You Ever Been to Prison (Rhodes)
      - 10. Dough Rolling Papa
      - 11. [unidentified] (Tampa Red)
      - 12. [unidentified]
      - 13. John Henry
      - 14. Why Don't You Do Right
      - 15. talk on Blind Willie
    - I-9 / 113 / 1318 / Indiana State Prison / #9: Blues / Eugene Rhodes / also #29 (Monan Scatological), 1962, AFC 2011/009: SR0895; 1 sound tape reel: analog, 3 1/2 ips and 7 1/2 ips, single track; 7 in.
    - I-10 / 114 / 1319 / Indiana State Prison / #10: Scatological / Prison / Gospel, March 10, 1962, AFC 2011/009: SR0896; 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
      - 1. Toasts - Ferguson
      - 2. Lawyer's Plea - Ferguson
      - 3. Dangerous Dan McGrew - Ferguson
      - 4. Birthday Cake - Ferguson
      - 5. Autobiographical data - Ferguson
      - 6. The Walls - Ferguson
      - 7. We're Not Living - Ferguson
      - 8. Precious Memories - Paschal and group
      - 9. Satan Done Tapped My Line
      - 10. One of those Days
    - I-11 / 115 / 1320 / Indiana State Prison / #11: Hillbilly, circa 1962, AFC 2011/009: SR0897; 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
    - I-12 / 116 / 1321 / Indiana State Prison / #12: Hillbilly and 17 Ernie Collins, circa 1962, AFC 2011/009: SR0898; 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
    - I-13 / 117 / 1322 / Indiana Reformatory, Pendleton / #12: Hillbilly (orig. was 1800 feet), circa 1962, AFC 2011/009: SR0899; 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
    - I-13A / 118 / Indiana Reformatory, Pendleton / #13a: Hillbilly, R & B / 1333, circa 1962, AFC 2011/009: SR0900; 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
    - I-15 / 119 / Indiana Reformatory, Pendleton / #15: Jokes / Blues / R & B / 1324, circa 1962, AFC 2011/009: SR0901; 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
    - I-17 / 120 / 1044 / Indiana State Prison / #17: Blues / Eugene Rhodes, April 20, 1962, AFC 2011/009: SR0746; 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
      Labels on the tape box are from the Archives of Folk and Primitive Music, Indiana University
      - 1. Talk on his conviction
      - 2. "I Keep Wonderin'" (he wrote)
      - 3. Talk on Buddy Moss, Blind Lemon Jefferson
      - 4. See That My Grave Is Kept Clean (fragment)
      - 5. Talk on Buddy Moss, Blind Boy Fuller
      - 6. She's Crazy Bout Me
      - 7. I'm Gonna Find My Woman (Fuller)
      - 8. C.C. Rider (6-string, walking bass)
      - 9. C.C. Rider (6-string, picking)
      - 10. C.C. Rider (6-string, chording)
      - 11. I'm Gonna Find My Woman (fragment)
      - 12. Tricks Ain't Workin' No More (12-string; fragment)